A Finding Aid to the Erwin Panofsky Papers, 1904-1990 (bulk dates 1920-1968), in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1921-1978, undated; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 1-16; 16 linear ft. Reels 2108-2128)
  - Colleagues, Scholars, Students and Other Individuals, 1921-1978, undated; 1.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Sessions - Setton, 1950-1967, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 15)
      Sessions, Barbara
      Settis, Salvatore
      Setton, Kenneth M.
    - Šev enko - Seymour, 1947-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 16)
      Šev enko, Ihor
      Sewall, John
      Sexton, Eric H. L.
      Seymour, Charles
    - Seyrig - Sheppard, 1946-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 17)
      Seyrig, Henri
      Sheldon, Alice D.
      Sheppard, Carl D.
    - Sherry, William Grant, 1961-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Shorr - Sjöquist, 1938-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 19)
      Shorr, Dorothy
      Shyrock, Richard H.
      Silverstein, Theodore
      Simon, Jules
      Simson, Otto von
      Sjöquist, Erik
    - Sladeczek - Smith, 1951-1967, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 20)
      Sladeczek, Leonhard
      Sloane, Joseph C.
      Smith, Nancy and E. Baldwin
    - Smyth, Craig, 1951-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 21-22)
    - Snell, Bruno, 1946-1971, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Snyder - Solberg, 1950-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 24)
      Snyder, James E.
      Solberg, Carl
    - Somitz, Walter and Elly, 1928-1963, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Sommer - Soth, 1949-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 26)
      Sommer, Frank H.
      Soper, Alexander Coburn
      Soth, Lauren
    - Speiser, David, 1960-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Spencer, 1951-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 28)
      Spencer, Eleanor P.
      Spencer, John R.
    - Speilberg, Ernest and Marie-Louise, 1951-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Spitzer, Leo, 1950-1956, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Springell - Starobinski, 1956-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 31)
      Springell, F.
      Stafski, Heinz
      Starobinski, Jean
    - Stechow, W., 1922-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 32-34)
    - Steck - Steinberg, 1940-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 35)
      Steck, Max
      Steegmuller, Francis
      Steinberg, Leo
    - Steinitz, Kate, 1945-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Sterling - Steneberg, 1954-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 37)
      Sterling, Charles
      Steneberg, Karl Eric
    - Stern, Henri, 1954-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Sternfeld, Frederick W., 1950-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Stillman - Strauss, 1931-1968, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 40)
      Stillman, Clark
      Stock, Brian
      Stoddard, Whitney S.
      Stokes, Muriel
      Stone, Lawrence
      Straus, Erwin W.
      Strauss, Lewis
    - Streisand - Stridbeck, 1953-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Streisand, Hugo
      Stridbeck, Carl G.
    - Strittmatter - Suida, 1950-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Strittmatter, Rev. Anselm
      Stubbe, Wolf
      Stubblebine, James H.
      Suida, W.
    - Swarzesnki, Georg, 1930-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Swarzenski, Hanus, 1931-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Sweeney - Szladitz, 1937-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Sweeney, J. J.
      Swoboda, Karl M.
      Symeonides, Sibilla
      Szladitz, Lola
    - T, General (single letters, Takashina - Tyler), 1940-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Takashina, Suji
      Tavel, Hans Christoph von
      Taylor, Michael A.
      Teasdale, Molly
      Ternbach, Joseph
      Theuerkauff-Leiderwald, Anna Elisabeth
      Thirby, Mrs. Edwin L.
      Thirlwall, John C.
      Thompson, Dorothy
      Thordeman, Bengt
      Thorne, Edgar F.
      Thullier, Jacques
      Tigerstedt, E. N.
      Tolman, Sally Jones
      Tomko, George Peter
      Tördten, Hans W.
      Toussiant, Rolf
      Tritscher, Walther
      Tritsch
      Turner, R.
      Tyler, Parker
    - Tarkington, Booth and Betty, 1938-1973, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
    - Tatarkiewicz - TenBroeck, 1937-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 9)
      Tatarkiewicz, Wlodyslaw
      Taubert, Johannes
      Taylor, Francis Henry
      Taylor, Sybil
      Temkin, Oswei
      Temko, Allan
      TenBroeck, Carl and Jane
    - Tervarent, Guy de, 1956-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Teyssèdre - Thompson, 1951-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 11)
      Teyssèdre, Bernard
      Thiem, Gunther
      Thompson, C. R.
      Thompson, Homer A.
      Thompson, Mary Lee
    - Thordeman - Thyssen-Bornemisza, 1961-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 12)
      Thyssen-Bornemisza, H. H.
    - Tietze, Erica, 1937-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Tolnay - Trinkaus, 1940-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 14)
      Tolnay, Charles de
      Tonelli, Giorgio
      Trapp. J. B.
      Trell, Bluma L.
      Treves, Marco
      Trinkaus, Charles
    - Tschmelitsch - Usher, 1950-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 15)
      Tschmelitsch, Günther
      Tselos, Dimitri
      Tilly, Mary Ann
      Tuve, Rosemund
      Ullman, B. L.
      Ullman, Pierre
      Ullmann, Ernst
      Underwood, Margaret
      Ungar, Emery U.
      Urken, Mrs. Paul
      Usher, Abbott P.
    - Van Isselt - Voss (single letters), 1942-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 16)
      Van Isselt, Harriette Van Dam
      Van de Velde, R. W.
      Van Doren, Irita
      Van Ghent, Dorothy
      Vanderbilt, Paul
      Verodn, Timothy C.
      Vescovini, G. Federici
      Vidal, Adrienne
      Viljoen, Helen Gill
      Viñals, Salvio G.
      Vogel, Amos
      Vogel, Bernard W.
      Vogel, Gerhard
      Vogelsang, W.
      Vogelstein, Hertha
      Volbach, Walther R.
      Vondracek, M. Jon
      Von Saldern, A.
      Voss, W.
    - Valentiner - Vasalle, 1942-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 17)
      Valentiner, W. R.
      Van Kuylen, Krister
      Van Nostrand, A. D.
      Varma, K. M.
      Vasalle, Rudolph A.
    - Veblen, Oswald, 1950-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Verdier, Philippe, 1949-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Verhaegen, Nicole, 1951-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Verheyen, Egon, 1960-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Verheyen, Egon, 1960-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Verheyen, Egon, 1960-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Verulam - Vinken, 1949-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 24)
      Verulam, Lord
      Vetter, Ewald M.
      Vierbeck, Peter
      Vinken, P.J.
    - Vöge, Wilhelm, 1924-1975, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 25-27)
    - Vossler, Otto, 1953-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - W, General (single letters, Waith - Wülfingen), 1926-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 29)
      Waith, Eugene M.
      Walle, A. Van de
      Wallen, Burr
      Wallington, Ian
      Wallis, Mieczyslaro
      Walters, Christian
      Walters, Gary
      Warburg, Erich M.
      Ward, John L.
      Ward, Mary C.
      Watson, George
      Wabinski, Zygmunt
      WBAI Radio
      Weadock, Gertrude
      Wearinga, Juw fon
      Weber-Marshall, J.
      Webster, Carson
      Wehle, Harry
      Weil, André
      Weilgart, Wolfgang J.
      Weinberg, Saul
      Weinberg, Gladys D.
      Weinberger, Edith
      Weingram, S.
      Weintraub, Viktor
      Weisgall, Nathalie
      Weisinger, Herbert
      Weisner, Ulrich
      Weitz, Morris
      Wesenberg, Rudolf
      While, Roy
      White, Christopher
      White, Howard B.
      Whitman, Robert F.
      Whitney, Hassler
      WHOM Radio
      Wickman, E. K.
      Wight, Frederick S.
      Wilber, Donald N.
      Wilde, Johannes
      Wildenstein, Daniel
      Wiles, R. M.
      Willard, Helen D.
      Wellliver, Warman
      Williams, Phyllis L.
      Willoughby, Harold R.
      Wilson, J. Christy
      Winslow, Harriet P.
      Winternitz, Emanuel
      Wirth, Karl-August
      Witt, Eobert
      Wohl, Hellmut
      Wolandt, Gerd
      Wolf, Gertrude
      Wolff, Eleanor L.
      Wolff, Helene
      Wood, Ledger
      Woodward
      Woody, William H., Jr.
      Woolf, Harry
      Wülfngen, Ordenberg Bock von
    - Waal - Wackernagel, 1947-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 30)
      Waal, H. van de
      Wace, Allen J. B.
      Wackernagel, Wolfgang D.
    - Walker, 1948-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 31)
      Walker, D. P.
      Walker, John
      Walker, Robert
    - Wallace, Richard W., 1959-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Warburg - Warren, 1940-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Warburg, Anita
      Warburg, Edward M. M.
      Warburg, Max
      Ward, Clarence
      Warren, Edith
    - Wasson, R. Gordon, 1950-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Waterhouse - Weinmann, 1946-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 4)
      Waterhouse, Ellis K.
      Webster-Bulatkin, Eleanor
      Weinberg, Bernard
      Weinberger, Martin
      Weinmann, Françoise
    - Weisinger, Herbert, 1946-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Weitenkampt - Weitzmann, 1951-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 6)
      Weitenkampf, Frank
      Weitzmann, Kurt
    - Weixlgärtner, Arpad and Josephine, 1950-1963, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Welliver - Wengroth, 1956-1958, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 8)
      Welliver, Mrs. Charles B.
      Welliver, Warman
      Welsh, Sue
      Wengroth, Stow
    - Wentzel, Hans, 1950-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Wershba - Wethey, 1941-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 10)
      Wershba, Joe
      Wescher, Paul
      Wethey, Harold E.
    - White, John, 1950-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - White, Lynn, 1938-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Wildenstein, Georges, 1945-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Will - Winkler, 1938-1967, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 14)
      Will, Frederic
      Willert, Paul
      Wilhelm, Pia
      Wilson, Larry
      Wind, Edgar
      Winkler, Friederich
    - Winternitz, Emmanuel, 1953-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Witte, Wilhelm, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Wittkower, Rudolph, 1936-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Woodford, Susan, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Wolff, Kurt, 1942-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Woodward, Llewellyn, 1957-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Wormald, Francis, 1937-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Wrightsman - Wuttke, 1953-1972, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 22)
      Wrightsman, C. B.
      Wuttke, Dieter
    - Xydis - Zeitler, 1945-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 23)
      Xydis, Stephen
      Yates, Frances
      Young, Mrs. T. R.
      Zados-Jitta, A. N.
      Zaffrani, Gian Franca
      Zannetti, Mario
      Zarnecki, George
      Zebal, Kinta A.
      Ziegermann, Erich
      Ziegermann, Peter
      Zeitlin, J.
      Zeitler, Rudolf
    - Zerner - Zupnick, 1937-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 24)
      Zerner, Henri
      Zigrosser, Carl
      Zilsel, E.
      Zimmerman, Mary H.
      Zucker, Paul
      Zupnick, I. L.
  - Art Dealers, 1932-1967; 1.2; Archival Resource Key
    Correspondence is available on reel 2124.
    - England (Colnaghi - Sotheby), 1950-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - France (Rheims and Baudoin), 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Holland/Netherlands (Kunsthandel P. de Boer), 1958-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - United States, Archival Resource Key (Box 13)
      - Mortimer Brandt Gallery, 1950-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Buchholz Gallery; Paul Drey Gallery, 1946-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 29)
      - Duveen Brothers; M. Knoedler; F. B. May Fine Arts, 1936-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 30)
      - Parke-Bernet Galleries; Rosenberg and Stiebel, 1948-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 31)
      - Schaeffer Galleries, Inc., 1936-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 32)
      - E. and A. Silberman Galleries, 1943-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Galleries and Museums, 1925-1968; 1.3; Archival Resource Key
    Correspondence is available on reel 2125.
    - Australia - National Gallery of Victoria, 1959-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Austria (Kunsthistorisches Museum), 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Belgium, Archival Resource Key (Box 13)
      - Damme (Museum van Maerlant), 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 36)
      - Antwerp (Musée Mayer van der Bergh; Musée Royale des Beaux Arts), 1949-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 37)
      - Ghent (Musée des Beaux-Arts), 1952-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Canada, Archival Resource Key (Box 13)
      - Kingston (Agnes Etherington Art Centre, Queen's University), 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 39)
      - Ottawa (National Gallery of Canada), 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 40)
      - Winnepeg (Winnipeg Art Gallery), 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - England, Archival Resource Key (Box 13)
      - Birmingham (Barber Institute of Fine Arts), 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 42)
      - Cambridge (Fitzwilliam Museum), 1948-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 43)
      - Leeds (City Art Gallery and Temple Newsam House), 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 44)
      - London (British Museum; National Gallery; Sir John Soane's Museum), 1925-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 45)
      - Manchester (Manchester City Art Gallery), 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 46)
      - Oxford (Ashmolean Museum), 1953-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 47)
      - York (City of York Art Gallery), 1955-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - France, Archival Resource Key (Box 13)
      - Aix en Provence (Musée Granet), 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 49)
      - Fontainebleau (Musée de Fontainebleau), 1956-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 50)
      - Lyon (Lyon Musée des Beaux-Arts), 1954-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 51)
      - Nancy (Musée des Beaux-Arts), 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 52)
      - Orléans (Musée des Beaux-Arts), 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 53)
      - Paris (Musée de Louvre), 1951-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 54)
    - Germany, Archival Resource Key (Box 13)
      - Berlin (Staatlichen Museen zu Berlin), 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 55)
      - Dortmund (Museum für Kunst und Kulturgeschichte Dortmund), 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 56)
      - Hamburg (Museum für Kunst und Gewrbe), 1951-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 57)
    - Holland/Netherlands, Archival Resource Key (Box 13)
      - Amsterdam (Rijksmuseum), 1951-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 58)
      - The Hague (Mauritshuis, Meermanno-Westreenianum), 1947-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 59)
      - ???sHertogenbosch, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 60)
      - Utrecht (Central Museum der Geneente Utrecht), 1951-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 61)
    - India (Baroda Museum and Picture Gallery), 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 62)
    - Israel (The Israel Museum), 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 63)
    - Italy, Archival Resource Key (Box 13)
      - Rome (Palazzo Barberini), 1951-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 64)
      - Urbino (Palazzo Ducale), 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 65)
    - Spain, Archival Resource Key (Box 13)
      - Cadiz (Museo Provinciad de Bellas Artes), 1953-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 66)
      - Madrid (Museo Arqueologico Nacional), 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 67)
    - Sweden (National Museum), 1952-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 68)
    - United States, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
      - California (Los Angeles County Museum of Art; Fine Arts Gallery of San Diego), 1953-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Connecticut (Wadsworth Athenaeum; Yale University Art Gallery), 1946-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - District of Columbia (Dumbarton Oaks, Harvard University; National Gallery of Art), 1946-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Florida (Ringling Museum), 1953-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Illinois (Art Institute of Chicago), 1951-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Indiana (Art Association of Indiana/John Herron Art Institute), 1944-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Kentucky (J. B. Speed Art Museum), 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Maine (Museum of Art of Ogunquit), 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - Maryland (Baltimore Museum of Art; Walters Art Gallery), 1958-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Massachusetts, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
        - Boston (Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum; Museum of Fine Arts), 1943-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 10)
        - Cambridge (Fogg Art Museum), 1933-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 11)
        - Northampton (Smith College Museum of Art), 1955-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 12)
        - Williamstown (Sterling and Francine Clark Art Institute; Williams College, Lawrence Art Museum), 1951-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 13)
        - Worcester (Worcester Art Museum), 1938-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - Michigan (Detroit Institute of Arts), 1943-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - Missouri (William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art), 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - Nebraska (Joslyn Art Museum), 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - New Jersey (Newark Museum; Princeton University Art Museum), 1940-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - New York, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
        - Brooklyn Museum; Buffalo Fine Arts Academy/Albright Art Gallery; Cornell University, White Art Museum; Cooper Union Museum, 1951-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 19)
        - Frick Collection, 1937-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 20)
        - Jewish Museum, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 21)
        - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1944-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 22-23)
        - Museum of Modern Art, 1951-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 24)
        - Rochester Memorial Art Gallery, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 25)
      - North Carolina (North Carolina Museum of Art), 1958-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 26)
      - Ohio, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
        - Cincinnati Art Museum; Cleveland Museum of Art, 1948-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 27)
        - Columbus Gallery of Fine Arts; Dayton Art Institute; Oberlin College, Allen Memorial Art Museum; Toledo Museum of Art, 1938-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 28)
      - Oregon (Portland Museum of Art), 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 29)
      - Pennsylvania, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
        - Alverthorpe Gallery, 1951-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 30)
        - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1950-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 31)
      - Rhode Island (Rhode Island School of Design Museum of Art), 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 32)
      - Texas (Museum of Fine Arts of Houston), 1949-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 33)
      - Vermont (Bennington Historical Museum and Art Gallery), 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 34)
      - Virginia, Norfolk Museum of Arts and Sciences; Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1954-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Libraries, 1941-1967; 1.4; Archival Resource Key
    Correspondence is available on reels 2125-2126.
    - Belgium (Bibliothèque Royale de Belgique), 1955-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Canada (Oratoire Saint-Joseph), 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - England, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
      - Canterbury (Lambeth Palace), 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 38)
      - London (Wellcome Historical Medical Library), 1957-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 39)
      - Oxford (Bodleian Library), 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - France, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
      - Paris (Bibliothèque de l'Arsenal; Bibliothèque Nationale), 1951-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 41)
      - Rouen (Bibliothèque de la Ville de Rouen), 1947-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - Germany (Universitäts-bibliothek), 1953-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Holland/Netherlands (Koninklinjke Bibliotheek), 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - Italy, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
      - Florence (Biblioteca Nazionale), 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 45)
      - Milan (Biblioteca Ambrosiana), 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 46)
      - Rome (Biblioteca Apostlica Vaticana), 1945-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 47)
    - Switzerland, Geneva (Bibliothèque, Universitaire), 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 48)
    - United States, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
      - California (Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery), 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 49)
      - District of Columbia (Library of Congress), 1947-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 50)
      - Illinois (Newberry Library; University of Chicago Library), 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 51)
      - Massachusetts, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
        - Boston Athenaeum, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 52)
        - Fogg Museum of Art Library, 1949-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 53)
        - Harvard University Library, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 54)
      - New Jersey, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
        - Institute for Advanced Study, 1952-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 55)
        - Princeton University, Firestone Library, 1954-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 56)
        - Princeton University, Marquand Library, 1951-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 57)
      - New York, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
        - Frick Art Reference Library; Jewish Theological Seminary Library, 1941-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 58)
        - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1943-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 59)
        - New York Public Library, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 60)
      - United States, Pennsylvania (Free Library of Philadelphia), 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 61)